[Music]
Good morning everybody and welcome to
episode 300 of 30 minutes the
president's club. My name is Arman Faro
and I'm here with my co-host Nick
Skielski and folks for 5 years straight.
Every single week whether it was when we
were on sales teams whether it was when
we were hanging out in Hawaii whether it
was in between vacation we have hopped
on this show. We have gotten on our mic.
We have packed our mics in our bag. And
we have interviewed a top seller or
leader out there in the world. And we
have become way, way, way, way better
sellers because of it. And our goal
today is to share with you 15 tactics
that truly changed the way that we sell
in the last 300 episodes. Nick, why
should people listen? Well, to your
point, across the last 5 years, we've
been exposed to some of the world's best
sales trainers, reps, and leaders who
literally sell in every single industry.
We've talked to people in SMB, in
mid-market, in enterprise. We've talked
to people selling real estate, selling
tech, selling services. And most of the
episodes we're like, damn, that was
really good. But there have been a very,
very select few where I'm like, that's
actually going to change the way I'm
showing up on my sales calls. And so
what we did is we distilled this episode
into the best of the best of the best of
literally the last 5 years. So you can
go pick up and steal and use this stuff
on your sales calls today. And so the
way we're going to go through this is we
have five categories and we have three
tactics per category. So three cold
calling tactics, three cold
email/overall prospecting tactics, three
discovery tactics, three sales process
or deal management tactics, and then
three leadership tactics. So Nick, let's
start with number one in the cold
calling category. Right. So the first
one in the cold calling category is
something that we learned from Jeb
Blunt, which is called the ledge, and it
is an objection handling technique. When
you get hit with an objection on a cold
call, I don't care how long you've been
cold calling, when you get smacked with,
"I'm not interested," or, "I'm in a
meeting," or, "We already have a vendor
for that," it hijacks your brain and it
shuts you down for a second. And in
order to overcome those objections,
you're going to have to be able to
respond moderately intelligently. But
it's impossible to do that when your
brain is literally hijacked. And so you
need a moment or two to be able to
figure out and recalibrate to figure out
how you should respond to that
objection. But you can't just sit there
and say, "Wait, hold on. Give me a
second." And so what Jeb recommends is
that you use a technique called the
ledge where you have a predefined
statement that you will use to buy
yourself that second before you actually
respond to the objection. So for me, my
ledge is the statement, "Shoot, this
one's totally on me." So, when I get hit
with the objection, I'm not interested,
my response is, this one's totally on
me. I guess you probably would have
reached out to me if you had been
interested, and then I can handle the
objection. When they tell me, hey, call
me in 6 months, my response is, "Shoot,
this one's totally on me." I guess I've
got a knack for calling people a couple
months before they're ready for stuff
like this. If they tell me they already
have a vendor in place, my response is,
"Shoot, this one's totally on me. I
should have figured you'd be using
something already." And so that's not
where I stop, but that gives me a second
to buffer against that emotional
turbulence that I get hit with when I
get hit with an objection. So that's
called the ledge. It's from Jeb Blunt.
Number two, this actually made it into
our cold calling book. And we learned
this from Jason Bay. It's called
chunking up. So a lot of times when
people try to articulate the problem
they solve to a senior executive, they
think, I don't need to get super
technical or tactical on the problem. I
need to get big picture high level. But
then they end up saying really generic
things like most CRO really care about
hitting their revenue targets. And while
that's true, you could literally be
selling any solution in the world if you
just talk about generic problems or
generic outcomes. So chunking up is when
you have a very very specific triggering
problem at the champion level and then
you chunk it up and you explain what it
means at the executive level. So, I'll
give you an example of a problem that I
would say to someone who's like below
the line. If I was selling compensation
software at PAVE, I might say like,
"Hey, Nick, look, the reason I'm
reaching out is during Q1 merit season,
most compensation teams are buried under
a mountain of spreadsheets with
literally like 17,000 VLOOKUPs." Now,
that's an operational problem that the
champion cares about, and that's going
to trigger them, probably get them to
book a meeting. But to get an executive
to care, I need to explain why that
spreadsheets problem leads to an
executive problem. And so I'm going to
say, look, Jay, the reason I'm reaching
out is usually during Q1 merit season,
most people leaders are freaking out
when they see their team buried under
spreadsheets running their merit cycles
like doing VLOOKUPs and stuff because it
actually becomes really hard to oversee
managers and making sure that they're
making equitable comp decisions. That's
an executive level problem that is
caused by a champion level problem. So
chunk your triggering problem up to the
executive level without losing
specificity if you're pitching to a C-
level. All right. So, the first tactic
that we've chunked together, Arman, for
this last takeaway around cold calling
is one way that you can open a cold call
that I use, which is called a tailored
permission opener. And what a tailored
permission opener is, there are three
pieces to your tailored permission
opener. The first thing that's going to
come out of your mouth when your
prospect answers the phone and they go,
"Hello," is not going to be your name.
It's not going to be an ask to tell them
why you called. It's literally going to
be something that you saw about them.
context for why you called them in the
first place. From there, you're going to
own that it's a cold call. And then
you're going to use the fact that you
led with something about them and you
were disarmingly honest about the fact
that this is a cold call as a way to get
permission to pitch. And so what that
might sound like is Armand answers the
phone and he goes, "Hello, I'm going to
say, Armand, I just finished reading the
press release about that office opening
y'all had in Tacoma." And I'm going to
be honest, this is a cold call, but it
is a fairly wellressearched one. And I'm
wondering if I can get half a minute to
share why that press release had
prompted me to call you. And then you
can totally hang up on me if it doesn't
make sense from there. What I'm doing is
I lead with that office opening. That's
something about Armand that can't be
templated or genericized. And that gets
him to sit up and pay attention. And
then I just tell him like, "Do you want
me to tell you why that office opening
press release made me call you?" And
that curiosity piece plus the fact that
I owned that this was a cold call
usually gets me permission to pitch. The
other opener that you can use is called
the heard the name tossed around opener
where your goal is for them to actually
forget that it's a cold call. So the key
here is you're going to lead with
something that shows that you work with
other people just like them. So if I was
calling another like sales podcast host,
I might be like, "Hey Jane, we work with
a few other guys over at um 30 minutes
to presence club. It's Arman from
Podcast Inc. Have you heard her name
tossed around?" Even if they haven't
heard my name tossed around, what
matters is they've heard 30 Minutes to
President's Club tossed around. And nine
times out of 10, they're going to sit up
and they're going to be like, "Oh, I'm
not going to be like a total jerk to
this person cuz they're working with
someone that I respect." One of the
biggest areas I see people screw that
one up, Armand is they think that like,
"What if they haven't heard my name
tossed around?" And that's not the goal
of that opener. The goal of the opener
is to make it seem like they should have
heard your name tossed around. So, you
have to act like they should have heard
your name before. Otherwise, it's going
to come across like, you know, you're a
rando, and it totally breaks sort of the
the frame you're setting up with that
opener. So, what happens after either of
these openers is you're going to
eventually have to tell your prospect
what the heck you do. And this is where
a lot of sales people end up shooting
themselves in the foot because they hit
their prospect with a value proposition
or pitch that the prospect's eyes and
ears just glaze over and they're like,
"Yeah, we're all set. I'm not
interested. Thanks anyways." The value
of your product doesn't really mean
anything to your prospect without the
context of a problem associated with it.
And so when you tell your prospect that
you have AI workflows or a single pane
of glass or a single source of truth or
back office optimization technology for
them, you're now putting the work on
them to figure out, okay, what am I
actually going to do with AI workflow
technology? and you're putting the hard
work on them to connect the dots of the
jobs that they have to do, the problems
they're dealing with, and how your tech
would make that go away. And so our
recommendation is instead of leading
with a value proposition, lead with what
we call a problem proposition where
you're actually going to articulate and
paint a movie scene of the biggest
hairiest problem that you think they
have that you can actually make go away.
So, if I'm selling billing software to a
law firm, my problem proposition is
going to sound something like, "Well,
look, Dave, the reason that I called you
is typically when I'm talking with a CFO
of an insurance defense law firm, folks
like you get driven crazy by all of the
deductions, the rejections, and the
appeals that you get when you send your
bills to your insurance carrier clients
because I know those folks will like
nitpick the bills to death. And if you
use the wrong word on the bill, they
refuse to pay for research or things
like that." Uh, and so we work with
about 300 other different law firms
helping them scrub their bills before
they even send them so that they don't
have to deal with those deductions and
rejections. I'm not sure if you're open
to learning more when I'm when I'm not
cold calling out of the blue, but that
was why I called you. And so if Dave,
the imaginary CFO in this scenario, has
that problem of the deductions,
rejections, and appeals that gets him
interested in hearing more about how we
can make it go away. So we have to get
them interested in the problem before we
can get them interested in the solution.
Most folks do it backwards. The last
piece is you're bound to get at least
one objection. And most sellers think
that they need to pitch or counter that
objection when in reality what you need
to do is you need to agree with the
objection and redirect the momentum of
that objection using what we call the
Mr. Miyagi method. So let's assume that
someone says, "I've got no budget." Step
number one is to agree with the
objection. So you might say something
like, "Nick, I totally get it, man.
Honestly, nowadays it's literally harder
to keep a tool, let alone buy something
new. When I do that, Nick's guard
immediately goes down. It's like he
tried to sit in a chair and I pulled it
out from underneath him because he's
like, "Wait, this person's not going to
try to sell me." But then from here, I
need to keep it going. So, step two is
called incentivizing conversation. So, I
need to give him a reason to tell me
more about the objection, which will
give me more information because I don't
have enough to handle the objection
accurately right now. So, I might say
this. Hey, Nick, just so no one calls
you again, could you give me sense of is
it just that budget is completely out
for this cycle or is it literally like
anything you're trying to spend money on
in perpetuity, like you get put through
the ringer on and have to put together
like 17 ROI cases for it? Which one is
it? So, number one, you want to say just
so no one calls you again to give them a
reason to give you a little bit more
about the objection. And then number
two, use multiple choice where you can
say like, "Hey, is it this, this, or
this?" to make it easy to answer your
question. From there, it doesn't really
matter that much what they say. What you
want to do in step three is you want to
sell the test drive, not the car. So, in
other words, like people don't want to
be pitched a product on a cold call, let
alone at all. And if you try to pitch
your product or even pitch a heavy
meeting, the reality is like most people
are just going to get turned off and
reject that on the front end. What you
want to do is you want to answer the
question, what is the reason that they
should take the meeting with you even if
they never buy the product? In other
words, you might have no desire to buy a
Tesla, but you probably at least want to
know how it drives. And that's called
selling the test drive. So, that might
sound like this. Hey, Nick. Honestly, my
guess is you're probably not going to
buy this thing, but the folks who end up
getting budget are usually the ones who
they they sort of know what's 1, two,
and three on their list. And so, my
guess is like this thing isn't going to
free up for quite a while. But like,
would you be open to taking a look at
this thing? Not for now, but just so you
know what's out there in case budget
does open up. That's the third step. And
then from there, once you get them in
the meeting, then you can talk about
what it means to secure budget once
you've actually proven out that there's
a problem we're solving. And that ends
the cold calling section and brings us
to cold email. Nick, what's number one
in the category of cold email? All
right, so the first one is something
that we learned from Ryan Riser, which
is called run the triple. And the
approach here is when you are cold
calling, you never want to make what is
called a naked dial. Your goal when
you're calling people and reaching out
to them. I saw the look on your face,
Arman. Don't worry, it's we're fully
clothed no matter what. But when you
call somebody, what you want to do is
you want to amplify the fact that you
are a real human being trying to get
their attention. And you also want to
make it as easy as possible for them to
respond to you. And so what Ryan
recommends is when you call somebody,
you shouldn't just call and move on. You
want to stack that touch with both an
email and a LinkedIn touch. So my first
step in my sequence or cadence, whatever
you're using, is literally an email, a
call, and a LinkedIn touch. And the goal
here is you want them to be like, whoa,
like this is actually a person. Here's a
face to a name. And when you email right
after the call or LinkedIn right after
the call, it makes it easier for them to
respond to you because the reality is
most people are not going to pick up the
phone and call you back. So run the
triple. You mostly do this on your first
touch where you email call LinkedIn in
very tight secession. But even the later
stages of your sequence, you're likely
going to be stacking email and LinkedIn
touches with your calls to the point of
being clothed, not making a naked dial.
Number two, Kyle Coleman, the master of
cold email himself, has personally
taught me a lot that influenced my own
cold email framework around a term
called resonance or the art of what we
call the segue. So, a lot of times
sellers will use random personalization.
So, they'll say things like, "Oh, Nick,
I noticed you wrestled at USC. I want
you to buy my building software." And it
has nothing to do with the problem that
they solve. And don't get me wrong, you
should put that stuff somewhere in the
email, but you should not think that
just because you happen to look at this
person's alma mater that that means that
they have a problem your business can
solve. So the framework for resonance or
relevant personalization is you want to
identify something that you know about
them and attach it to a problem that you
can solve. And those are the first two
paragraphs of every good cold email.
Something I see about you, what that
problem means for your business. So, a
couple of examples. If I was selling
legal billing software, if I knew you
just won a big case, that would mean
that I knew you were about to have to
deal with collecting a bunch of money,
which I could help with. If I was
selling a 30MPPC sponsorship and I saw
that you just launched a parallel
dialer, that means you're probably
competing with all the other parallel
dialers out there. If I was selling
compensation software at pave, I could
say, "Oh, I just saw that you post ahead
of compensation job posting, which means
you're probably cleaning up and taking
it a lot more seriously than you used to
because now you have enough risk in your
business where you need to tighten up
compensation. So, always, always, always
have a trigger that is attached to a
relevant problem that you can solve and
then you can segue into your one-s
sentence solution for that problem and a
low friction call to action." Armon, how
do I actually do this at scale? This
seems like it's going to take a lot of
time. Well, I have a third tactic for
you. It's called trigger templates. And
this is from the one and only Charlie
Johnson. Charlie Johnson has probably
influenced me the most when it comes to
learning how to personalize at scale.
Now, here's a trick. Take those three
triggers and all you have to do is
templatize those two sentences. I
noticed this about you, which means you
have this problem. Templatize those
first two sentences and you can keep the
rest of your email the same. So have
three, four, or five triggers where you
just look for those five things on an
account and then pop in trigger
templates for each of those things and
you can literally send hyperpersonalized
emails at scale that are problembased
and relevant without having to reinvent
the wheel every single time. That brings
us to the conclusion of the prospecting
and cold email category. If you follow
the tips that we shared, you're probably
going to be booking some meetings.
You're going to get some discovery calls
on the books. So, Arman, let's roll into
the discovery section of the tactics
that changed the way that we sell.
Great. Number one is from episode number
one of all time. Joe Caprio, PPO,
purpose, plan, outcome. And he actually
got this from Doug Landis, who was
another guest, funny enough. But this is
literally the way that I set an agenda
for any meeting in the sales cycle. A
lot of times sellers will focus on
things like, "Oh, the purpose of today's
call is to do a demo." And that's
actually not true. The purpose of the
call is not to do a demo. Plan for the
call is that we're going to do a demo.
The purpose of us doing a demo is for us
to figure out whether or not our
solution is actually going to solve a
problem for you. The plan is this is how
we're going to spend time to make sure
that we can actually like prove out the
purpose. And then the outcome is that
the end of this call, you and I can have
a frank discussion around like whether
or not it even makes sense for us to
take a next step, which might look like
a P, but that should only happen if you
really like what you see in the demo
today. You do that to start every
discovery call. You do that to start
every demo call. You do it to start
every single executive call. Purpose,
plan, outcome. The next technique that
we learned comes from KD Kevin Dorsy,
and it is called bucket questions.
Bucket questions are a technique that
you can use to guide the conversation
you're having with your prospect in the
direction of problems that you solve
while simultaneously establishing some
credibility for yourself because the way
that you're asking this question shows
that you know the common problems or
pain points or focuses of the person
that you're talking to. So a really
basic example of this would be I used to
sell ERP software to law firms Armand
and a thing that we would frequently
hear from the COOs we were talking to
would be something along the lines of
yeah we're really looking to optimize
our back office operations. A nonbucket
question that doesn't steer the
conversation in places that we can solve
and makes me sort of look like a buffoon
is oh well what are your pain points
with your back office processes? A
bucket question would be, "Okay, cool.
Well, we're typically able to help with
stuff like that, Arman. I guess I'm
curious." Usually, when I'm talking to
COOs and they're thinking about back
office optimization, like there's two
main places folks might be focused on.
Place one would be around new client
intake. I know I've heard from a lot of
folks that it can be really, really slow
and manual and prevent your attorneys
from actually working on cases when they
come in. The other place that I've been
hearing has been around like billing and
assembling bills because there have been
a lot of new changes with the way
insurance companies like process bills.
I guess I'm curious, do you feel like
new client intake or billing is more of
a focus for you? And what I'm doing here
is I'm laying out the buckets of the
places that I know we can really really
help with that I am certain they're
struggling with as a way to steer and
guide the conversation toward places
that we can actually sell and solve to.
I'm next. Okay, Nick, I recognize this
is an awkward question, but do do you
know who has the next tactic? I do,
Arman. It is the legendary Charles
Mulbau, the king of discovery, who if
you're not following on LinkedIn, you
should be. One of the things that
totally changed selling for me was the
first episode we had with Charles, where
he taught me the concept of the humbling
disclaimer. And the humbling disclaimer
is a technique that you'll use any time
that you need to have a direct
conversation with your prospect or ask
them a really hard question or ask them
about something really sensitive. And so
this might be if you're asking about
things like timeline, like when are they
actually planning on making a decision
and signing a contract or budget. Have
they actually set aside budget for
something like this? Or you might be
asking about like, hey, you're in a
tough competitive battle. what does it
actually take to beat competitor B? And
it can be kind of weird for you to just
like say to your prospect, so Arman, do
you have budget set aside for this? And
that will put some prospects on the
defensive. Or if you're asking about
you've done a great job at discovery and
you've gotten all the way to like impact
and you're at the point where it's like,
oh, it's clear that like they might lose
their job or have to lay people off if
they don't solve this problem. You can't
just be callous and be like, so it it
feels like you're probably going to have
to lay people off if you don't solve
this problem. that's like a little too
on the nose and it's going to put your
prospect on the defensive and get them
to clam up. And so what Charles
recommends is using this technique
called the humbling disclaimer to just
soften those tough asks where all you're
going to do is you're going to take that
like sort of uncomfortable feeling that
you have asking this direct thing. I
still have those feelings on sales
calls. And you're going to soften the
ask by saying something like, you know,
Armand, I recognize this is sort of a
sensitive question. or Arman, you know,
I know this might be a weird thing to
ask you. Or Armand, I'm I'm not even
sure how to ask you this, but and you
take those statements and you put them
before the tough direct question, and it
makes you seem far more human. It
softens the ask, and you're actually
more likely to have the prospect say,
"Hey, you know what? I know that's not a
weird question. That's actually
something that I've thought about
before." And so, use the humbling
disclaimer before you have a hard ask of
your prospect. The other question that
is my favorite discovery question that I
learned from Charles is called the magic
moment question and it's really simple.
Whenever someone admits to having a
problem, just ask them, "When was the
moment that you realized that that was a
problem and you will almost always get a
painful story and stories are usually
the bridge between operational problems
and executive problems." So, for
example, if Nick is like, "Oh man, like
I'm just like really struggling to like
oversee these manager compensation
decisions." I might say like, "Totally
get it, Nick. We see this all the time.
Like, hey, my guess is you didn't wake
up yesterday and think like, oh man,
like I have no idea what's going on with
these managers. I guess like when did
you realize this was a problem in the
first place? Was it like you saw a
manager going rogue on decisions? Is it
just like you woke up in a cold sweat or
is it something else? And almost always
they will go on a long rant about that
one manager who made a ridiculous
compensation decision that was totally
out of whack and it was because they
were planning compensation in
spreadsheets. That finishes the
discovery category and it brings us to
deal process and number one in the deal
process category comes from my number
one seller ever, Morgan Melo. And so
there are a number of things that I've
learned from Morgan, but what she's
probably absolutely best at is her
ability to build and test champions. So
there are three mini tactics within this
one. The first is the champion sandwich.
So once you finish up a discovery and a
demo with your champion and you're
getting ready to go present to the big
team, you want to set three meetings.
Yes, three meetings. The big team
meeting with the exec goes in the middle
and then you do a champion prep call
before and a champion debrief
afterwards. So your champion prep call
gets you on the same side of your
champion and they give you inside
baseball and what's to come in that big
team meeting. And then the debrief call
always gets scheduled before so that
you're not on this big team meeting like
being like, "Hey, all right, who's who
wants to take a next step here?" Right?
So that's number one. You got the
champion sandwich. From there, once you
actually start to meet with your
champion, you can start to test them by
asking like, "How do you plan to justify
this internally?" And that will usually
tell you whether your champion is going
to be talking about your solution in
above the line or below the line terms
and whether or not you really need to
like contain their narrative, put
together really tight business cases and
videos so that it's not really them
talking to the org, it's you talking to
the org. And then lastly, number three,
once you're done with that first
champion prep call, that is the best
time to get the digits of your champion.
Be like, "Hey, could I text you after
this big team meeting just to get a
sense from you, like to get a sense of
how this thing went?" Nine times out of
time they will say yes because you're
trying to make them look good.
Beautiful. Okay, that brings us to our
next one which is a pricing approach
that we learned from Bel on his first
appearance. I think he's been five times
on the show now. This is called popcorn
pricing and is a pricing strategy. So I
want you to think about the last time
that you went to the movie theater,
Armand, you go to the big board, you're
going to get some concessions. You got
your Coca-Cola, your candy, and you're
like, I'm ready for some popcorn.
There's three different sizes of popcorn
at the movie theater. You've got your
small popcorn which costs $6 and it's
like a couple kernels that literally
nobody but an infant would be satisfied
by eating. That's six bucks. Then you've
got your medium popcorn. That's like
enough for a normal human being. It's
probably the right amount of popcorn for
one person and that costs $7. And then
you've got the extra large popcorn,
which is enough popcorn to feed a family
for an entire week. It's a massive
overflowing thing. And it costs not $8,
but $7.50. And the reason that movie
theaters price popcorn this way is
they're trying to maximize their deal
size. And if you think about what
popcorn actually costs the movie
theater, the difference for their costs
between the medium and the large is
probably 3. And so what they're looking
to do is they're actually using
psychology as a way to guide you towards
that biggest popcorn, which is more than
you really need, but it's such a better
deal. Like the price per kernel is so
much better than the medium or the small
that they use the medium and the small
to anchor you to what popcorn should
cost. And that makes the extra large
seem like a great deal. And so you can
actually do the same thing with what you
are selling. What you want to do is if
you have options for modules that you
can sell or the way that you sell
professional services, what you want to
do is if you set up multiple packages,
the value of the packages should not
increase in a linear fashion. Meaning
the largest tier should be the most
valuable as a way to steer them up in
that direction. And so think about there
are things that you can likely offer
whether it is a second instance of the
software or additional licenses or
training hours or pre-purchase
professional services hours or a module
that like doesn't cost you and your
company anything that you can put into
that biggest tier as a way to drive
people to the most valuable package. So
use popcorn pricing as a way to increase
your average deal size. And the last one
is yo-yo selling from Ian Kak, the
number one all-time producer over at
Salesforce who has closed multi multi
multi-million dollar deals and had
multiple seven figure W2 checks. The way
that you get an enterprise deal closed
is not by this long ground swell motion
is you need to start by finding an
executive sponsor. So that's the top of
the deal. Let's say for example you meet
with a COO or a president. That's your
first meeting. From there, you don't
want to deal fatigue that person and
bring them through seven more calls. You
want to get permission from them to run
an assessment with all of their
department leads. So, the COO might
introduce you to their VP of revenue,
their VP of customer success, their VP
of operations. And what that does is it
tells them, hey, take this thing
seriously. And then it gives you a
reason to report back results after
you've done deeper discovery with each
of those department leads. So the yo-yo
goes and you run three separate sales
cycles with each of those department
leads. And then you stitch it all
together and you bring back the results
to that executive buyer in the upswing
of the yo-yo. So to recap, you start at
the executive, you win over the
department leads, and you report the
results back up to the executive. That's
yo-yo selling. We're down to the last
three. Arman, we launched our leadership
show. I think it was two years ago when
we brought Mark Kasaglow on as one of
the co-hosts of that and I've gotten to
join for some of those episodes and
we've learned some things that have also
changed how we think about sales
leadership. So, let's get into that. The
first one is the only person on this
list, Arman, who I think made it on
twice, which is Katie Kevin Dorsy, and
it is to document the wiggle and
practice forward. So, let's start with
document the wiggle. Wiggle stands for
WG LL, what good looks like. And what
you want to do as a sales leader is it's
one thing to tell your reps, hey, here's
what to do or here's the way you need to
approach this meeting or here's why we
do things this way. It's another to show
them how. And so anytime you have
something that actually matters in your
sales process, talk tracks, demo flows,
negotiation best practices, you need to
have documentation of like what that
being executed actually looks and sounds
like. And so whether that is call
recordings, whether that whether that is
examples of emails that have booked
meetings, you need to make it extremely
obvious for the entire team the behavior
that they need to replicate. Don't make
people go from, okay, I know this is
what I need to do, let me figure out how
to do it. Literally enable them with the
how. Now, once you've done this, once
you've documented the wiggle, you've
reinforced it, you've helped the team
get up to good. The next piece is the
way that you approach practice with your
team. One of the things Katie talks
about is like you can't just stumble
into a meeting and expect the words to
come out of your mouth the right way the
first time, especially in something like
sales where there's so many different
contingencies and situations that you
get thrown into. And what KD's approach
is, what a lot of sales leaders will do
is they'll ask a rep, "Hey, how did that
meeting last week go? Let's dig in. Oh,
shoot. We're looking at the call
recording. We need to practice. You
didn't set an agenda." Well, well, what
you actually need to do, what KD has
taught us, is first identify places that
the reps and the team needs to get
better. And instead of retroactively
practicing by saying, "Hey, here's what
you screwed up." Instead, practice for
meetings that are coming in the future.
So, when you're in your one-on-one with
a rep, pull up the calendar and say,
"All right, what are the most important
meetings next week? What are some of the
moments that you need to nail? And then
spend some time in that meeting
practicing the way that they're going to
set the agenda with that tough exact or
the game plan for the negotiation.
Literally roleplay the negotiation for
that meeting that they have next week.
And when you practice for the future,
you're actually driving outcomes as
opposed to just venting and being upset
about something that you can't change
because it happened in the past. Number
two is the fivestage sales process from
my lovely other co-host, Mark Kasaglo.
And so Mark really changed the paradigm
for me when it came to running pipeline
reviews and overall like figuring out
when a deal has actually moved to the
next step versus another meeting has
just happened to have happened. So what
you want to do is if your sales stages
sound like discovery, demo, executive
meeting, proposal, that is called an
activity-based stage management. And the
reason that that is a broken form of
sales stage management is because
discovery is one meeting. But what if
you don't find a problem in that one
meeting? Or what if you're able to do
discovery and demo in one meeting and
you can get problem and solution
agreement and maybe you can even get a
proposal out too. Well then your stages
are totally irrelevant. What you need to
actually do is you need to flip it and
you need to change your stages to what
are you trying to get in each stage. So
for example, we oftentimes describe
stage two instead of demo as solution
agreement. You need to get your prospect
to say yes, I believe that your solution
is the best to solve my problem. And
there are 10 different ways that you can
do that. You can do that through a demo.
You can do that through a PC. You can do
that through case studies. You could do
that through a reference. You could do
that in five calls. You could do it in
one call lumped in a discovery. But the
reality is all that matters is you need
to get your prospect to make a decision
in that stage, not just do a random
activity for the sake of doing an
activity. For reference, the sales
stages that we use here for our deals at
30 minutes to President's Club, stage
one is literally called problem
agreement. Stage two is called solution
agreement. Stage three is called power
problem and solution agreement. You need
power to also agree to those things in a
deal. Stage four is called commercials
agreement and stage five is called
vendor review. The exit criteria for
that is a closed one deal. And by
renaming those stages, Armont, it's
changed the way that we are actually
talking about our deals because it is
front and center on our deal board.
Boom. And the last one is a personal one
that Nick has called out was very
helpful. So I threw it on this list
which is called inverting the hiring
funnel. So, a lot of people make the
mistake, especially in early stage
selling, where they think they're
Salesforce, and they're like, I'm going
to post a job, and I'm going to get 500
applicants, and I'm going to screen 500
applicants down to 100, and then I'm
going to keep grilling the living
daylights out of all of my candidates,
and then by the end, they're going to
want to work for me. And the problem is,
number one, a lot of the best candidates
need to be sold into doing some of those
tests in the first place. Number two, a
lot of decisions are actually made in
the first and second meetings in an
interview process. And so instead of
trying to get a thousand candidates to
be 10 and then hope that of those 10,
three will actually accept, you're going
to invert the hiring funnel. You're
going to spend as much time as possible
with your top 10 candidates and you're
going to sell them upfront. So that
first interview is actually 75% selling
and 25%
evaluating. And then that earns you the
right to almost use like a
permissionbased opener to ask them for
permission to grill them and then op
them into the process. Now they're far
more likely to take the test seriously
because they're sold on the interview.
And then at the end, you know they're
going to accept the offer because you
sold them on the front end instead of
trying to sell them on the back end of
the interview process. Arman, that
brings us to our conclusion. And before
we recap, I'm actually wondering if I
can ask you a question, which is we've
been doing this for five full years and
we've learned a ton about how to sell,
but there's still more that I'm learning
every single week and I imagine there's
stuff that you're learning. And so I'm
curious like what are some of the things
that you would like to learn from our
guests over the the next 5 years? You
know, I was having dinner with Johnny
Larson last night who's multiple time
guest, one of our greatest and his
manager was there, really mildmannered
guy and was the number one global leader
at Talk Desk Sales Kickoff. Of his seven
reps, all seven of them went to
President's Club. And this guy was the
quietest guy at the table. like did not
was not beating your chest or anything
like that. Very mildmannered guy. And so
I sat next to him eventually. I was
like, I I sort of want to figure out
what this guy's all about. Like he's
clearly very good. He's he's a super
humble guy. And one of the things that
he was talking about is he's like, I
don't tell anyone what to do. He's like,
I I I try to help people figure out
their way to do things because my way is
a very different way from your way,
which is a very different way from their
way. And I think I did a decent job of
that in sales. But when I think about
that as just an overall leadership
characteristic, whether it's like
teaching someone to write in the 30 MPC
style, teaching someone to manage
projects in the way that I like to
manage them, I can honestly tend to be
like pretty prescriptive. And what that
ends up leading to is like someone ends
up just being like a slightly lesser
carbon copy of me trying to emulate a
style that isn't theirs. So figuring out
like how to find strike that balance
when I'm coaching people between giving
guard rails so they don't go all over
the place and literally just like
micromanaging the living daylights out
of someone having to have something be
perfect is something that I'm honestly
still working on a lot. Still trying to
balance. Nice. What about so glad you
asked? I think I think for me one thing
that I'm so obviously like I'm
interested in seeing how sellers are
going to continue to use AI as it
continues to evolve over the next 1 3 5
10 years. And so I know that there's
going to be changing best practices and
worst practices related to that. And I
think one offshoot of that is we have
the ability to access like very detailed
information in a second about our
prospects. Like I was reading on
LinkedIn someone made a post about like
here's how I can use six different
prompts to prepare for my discovery
calls. And I think there's going to
start to be a chasm between like ability
to access information and then like the
way that we actually show up on the call
and like hold our ground with a tough
executive because you don't have the
luxury of like being able to chat GPT
your way through a call when you're like
face to face with another human being.
And so I'm interested more in learning
about like some of like executive
presence and like the little things like
thinking about like the Ian Kia yo-yo
ask for permission or we've talked about
people that are like leading with a
point of view. Nate Nazala talked about
like the executive one minute pre-eread
and I so I think understanding how folks
that might be a bit more junior in their
careers can start to get respect and
credibility with executives and that's
not always just like a easy tactical
thing but I know there's more we can
uncover with that and then I think one
other thing is like I know there's going
to be more changes to prospecting
especially with the AI stuff and so
understanding what folks are doing to
cut through the noise. was talking with
my mom about this. She was telling me
about when email rolled out and
everybody was like losing their minds
over email and like at one point just
sending somebody an email was definitely
enough to get their attention. And so I
know that sellers will evolve in ways to
cut through the noise that's being
created right now with different
channels and approaches and I'm eager to
learn about like what's cutting edge
related to that. Well folks, 300
episodes, 15 tactics. Most importantly,
the only reason that we were actually
able to go 300 episodes wide is because
you all showed up every single week. You
continue to listen and you know, I'm
fortunate enough to live in New York
where I get to walk around the streets
and see like a lot of people working in
tech or other sales careers. And I would
say that like every other week someone
comes up to me randomly on the streets
and says like, "Your podcast changed the
game for me." And there are a million
and one stories out there like that. And
folks, the reason that we are able to be
full-time on this and spend so much time
in front of the mic and interviewing the
best sellers in the world is because you
all show up every single week and you're
trying to get yourselves to President's
Club. So, thank you for listening for
300 episodes. Whether you've been here
from episode number one or whether
somehow this is literally your first
episode, you landed on a good one,
folks. We will see you next time at
President's Club. All righty. Peace out.
[Music]